David Shaw

Cottonwood Heights, UT 84047 david.shaw1242@gmail.com (801) 891-0585

Portfolio: https://david-shaw-portfolio.netlify.app/ Github: https://github.com/ds1242

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/david-shaw1242

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer and Utah Army National Guard veteran with six years of Business Analyst experience and a degree in Information Systems from the University of Utah. Recently earned a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Utah. Skills in React, JavaScript, and Node.js. Always learning new technologies and striving to create impactful web applications for end users. A wide array of previous experiences provide me with a unique perspective to know when and what questions to ask to ensure that applications provide the best results and utility for end users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL

Applications: GitHub, MySQL

Tools: Express, React, Node.js, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Mongoose, Heroku

PROJECTS

The Underground | https://floating-lake-70395.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Web app where users can create personal profiles, add details for a personal show, and comment on other user's upcoming shows.
- Role: Full stack collaborator for a group project
- Tools: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Dotenv, Bootstrap, GraphQL, Mongoose, Bcrypt, React Router, JSON Web Token, Javascript

Secret Show | https://github.com/ds1242/secret-show-v2 | https://secret-show.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Website where small bands and their fans can find upcoming shows and their locations. Users can also preview the band's music prior to the show with the YouTube API
- Role: Full stack collaborator
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, iFrame,

David's Tech Blog | https://github.com/ds1242/tech-blog | https://guarded-cliffs-83768.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Self built blog web application that allows users to login, create blog posts, and comment on other user's posts.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Node.js, Sequelize, Handlebars, Express, Dotenv, Bcrypt

EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst II August 2018 - Present

Intermountain Healthcare

Murray, UT

- Provide support for day-to-day operation maintenance and support to users ensuring business critical activities continue uninterrupted
- Managed and Implemented a new approval process which streamlined payment activities and avoided potentially costly late fees of several thousand dollars and payment issues due to an unsupported legacy system
- Created training materials and documents for over a hundred users as resources needed to conduct daily operations
- Onboarded and implemented a new software interface to modernize legal tracking and payments ensuring timely legal payments

Business System Analyst

April 2015 – February 2018

Dell EMC

Draper, UT

- Collected requirements to develop use cases and documentation for development
- Formalized and implemented a development cycle for an active business critical application using waterfall methodology
- Collaborated and worked with team members remotely or in a virtual environment
- Assembled requirements, identified security gaps, and wrote documentation to integrate hardware and software from a newly acquired business entity
- Wrote SQL gueries to assist creation of user stories
- Received the Silver level recognition award for accurate and timely project delivery in 2016

Quality Assurance Intern

September 2013 – April 2015

University of Utah

Salt Lake City, UT

- Automated and manually tested applications based on user requirements
- Wrote testing requirements and managed the other interns in testing which ensured the smooth release of a new application form for potential future students to the university
- Functioned on a team with Scrum agile development managed through JIRA
- Exposure to writing test scripts using Ruby and Selenium
- Assisted with release management of projects throughout the development process
- Led QA team meetings on a rotating basis
- Wrote SQL queries to test applications

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – University of Utah

August 2021

Salt Lake City, UT

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems – University of Utah

May 2015

Salt Lake City, UT